Ruth Krauss Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Poetry Pilot, Dec. 1973, Jan. 1974, Feb. 1974, May-July 1974, Sept. 1974, Jan. 1975, Oct. 1975, Nov. 1976, June 1977, Sept. 1977, April-May, 1978, Oct. 1979, June 1980.
Poetry Project, 127.
Poetry Project Newsletter, 2-17, 20, 27-28, 30-32, 36-37, 50, 54, 68, 72, 74-75, 77-78, 86-87, 91-92, 95, 104, 106, 115, 118-19, 121, 125
Poetry: So What?, 1.
Poets & Writers, 15:5, 16:1, Supplement Summer 1976.
Pogamoggan, 1.
Poor Old Tired Horse, 18, 19
Proteus Magazine, 5.
Provident Bookfinder, 14:1.
Provincetown Review, 7.
Pucker Safral Gallery Newsletter, 16:1.
Residu, 1.
Rhinelander Newspaper, 4.
Samisdat, 42:1.
Semi-Colon, 1:1-2, 2:2-6
Sinking Bear, 5, 8.
Sixties, 10.
Small Press Review, 8:3, 8:5, 5, 39.
Some, 7/8.
Strange Faeces, 5-7, 20.
Sun, 3:2-3
Sunbury, 5 (2:2, Summer 1976)
Synanon Literary Journal, 1-2.
Synapse, 3:2, 3, 4.
Telephone, 2-6, 8-9, 11, 14-16, 18-19, one unnumber issue
Theater Crafts, 1:1.
Time, 30 Nov. 1962.
Tom Veitch Magazine, 3.
Toothpaste, 5-7.
Triquarterly, 43.
United Sisters Magazine, 2:3.
University of Tampa Poetry Review, 6.
University Publishing, 4.
Village Voice, 10:20.
Waterfall, 7:1.
Waterways, 2:4.
Westport Art Center, Jan. 1988, May 1988.
Wild Dog, 10-11, 13-20.
Women Artists Newsletter, 2:3.
Women/Poems, 2.
The World, 1, 5, 10-12, 20-21, 23-25, 28-29, 36, 38
Writing, 9.
Writer's Workshop, Winter 1971-72
WRL News, 181.
X by X, Spring, 1963.
Yaddo Newsletter, 3:1.
Postcards
Bifford Press, Poets' Dozen.
Burning Deck, 3rd Ten.
Burning Deck, 4th Ten.
Felsenthal, Peter, "Poem" (1983).
Heinrich, Peggy, "Bag People" (1983).
Heinrich, Peggy, "Letters" (1983).
Heinrich, Peggy, "Pacific Stone" (1983).
Krauss, Janet, "Still Points" (1983).
Lans, Barbara E., "Departure" (1983).
Lans, Barbara E., "I Keep Travelling" (1983).
Littledale, Freya, "Surprises" (1983).
Lund, Doris, "Poem" (1983).
Olesen, Candace A., "Grammar for Dog Days" (1983).
Catalogs
Toothpaste Press Catalog (no date).
Multimedia
Audio Cassettes, unidentified, 8.
Audio Tapes (Reel to reel), 2.
Authors of the Month: Bill Martin Jr. and John Archambault (audio cassette).
Bentley, Eric, Eric Bentley Sings "The Queen of 42nd Street" and Other Songs (LP).
Boogie Woogie (LP set).
Broughton, James, The Bard and the Harper (LP).
Contact sheet, Crocket Johnson and Ruth Krauss, 1.
Ellington, Duke, The Duke (LP set).
Jacques Brel is Alive and Well and Living in Paris (LP set).
Kuralt, Charles, narrator, The Incredible Year (LP).
Lead Belly and the Golden Gate Quartet, "The Midnight Special" and other Southern Prison Songs (LP set).
"A Letter to Amy" (short 33 1/3 record).
Levine, Dr. Henry "Hotlips" and his Barefoot Dixieland Philharmonic, NBC's Chamber Music Society of Lower Basin Street (LP set).
Long, Lee, "The Wedding Song" / "Til Tall" (45 record).
LP sets, unidentified, 2.
Marais and Miranda, Ballads of Long Ago (LP).
Marais, Josef, and his Bushveld Band, Songs of the South African Veld (LP set).
Matilda by Roald Dahl (audio cassette).
"Mickey's Magnet" (short 33 1/3 record).
"Mozart: Sonata in C Major" (LP).
Peter and the Wolf (LP set).
Rose, Norman, narrator, The Carrot Seed (short record).
Tatum, Art, Decca Presents Art Tatum (LP).
Video Cassettes (VHS Format), 2.
Weston Wood Studios, Children's literature, 2 LPS.
Zeisl, Eric, Pieces for Barbara / Children's Songs (LP set).
Bibliography
Nel, Philip. The Crockett Johnson Homepage Online. July 11, 2003.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Krauss, Ruth.; Leisk, David.; Johnson, Crockett, 1906-1975.; Sendak, Maurice.; O'Hara, Frank.; Hausman, Gerald.
Organizations:
Greenwillow Books.; Scholastic Books.; Harper Publishing.
Subjects:
Children's literature, American--20th century.; Children's literature--Connecticut authors.; Children's literature--Connecticut illustrators.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Photographs.; Financial Records.; Press releases.; Artwork.; Videocassettes.; Audio cassettes.; Audio visual materials.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Illustrations.; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.; Typescripts.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Books.; Sketches.; Drawings.; Posters.; Patents.; Albums.; Contracts.; Sound recordings.; Poems.; Newsletters.; Newspapers.; Filmstrips.; Broadsides.
Occupations:
Author.; Poet.; Illustrator.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
In 1993, the estate of Ruth Krauss contacted the Northeast Children's Literature Collection at the University of Connecticut to donate the papers. The estate transferred custody of the papers to the NCLC on 3 August 1993.
Acquisition Information
The estate of Ruth Krauss gave physical custody of the Ruth Krauss papers to the NCLC in 1993. The papers were officially donated to the University of Connecticut Libraries on 7 July 1994.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1947-1991
  - Subseries A: Correspondence to Krauss, undated, 1947-1991
    Note: Includes correspondence written to Ruth Krauss. Correspondence is filed by last name of the sender, when known, or by corporate name.
    - A, 1952 September - 1982 June (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - A.E. Fales Elementary School, 1991 May 6 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Atheneum Publishers, 1963 March - April (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - B [Note from James Broughton on Remy Charlip's artwork.], 1964 July - 1988 October (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Barlow Mountain School, 1975 March (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Barlow Mountain School, undated (Box 18:, Folder 646)
    - Ballantine Books, 1985-1986 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - C, 1964 May - 1990 July (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Chase, Naomi Feigelson, 1970 January (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Children, 1967 April - 1990 May (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Children, 1987 October (Box OS:, Folder 663)
    - Children, undated (Box 18:, Folder 648)
    - Clermont Elementary School, 1987 March 16 (Box 18:, Folder 647)
    - Curtis Brown Limited, 1963 April - 1979 July (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - D, 1972 August - 1982 April (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - E, 1984 July - 1990 November (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - F, 1958 May - 1987 September (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Freilicher, Marvin, undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - G, 1955 November - 1988 December (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Greenwillow Books, 1976 June - 1984 July (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Griffith, E.V./Poetry Now, 1975 January - 1983 May (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - H, 1962 October - 1984 April (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - Harcourt, Brace, and Company, 1962 October - 1990 January (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Harper and Brothers [Includes letters from Ursula Nordstrom], 1947 July - 1963 March (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Harper and Row, 1962 October - 1990 January (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Harper Collins, 1991 March (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - Hausman, Gerald, 1975 January - 1982 February (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, 1989 July - August (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - I, 1975 July (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - J, 1980 November - 1986 December (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - K, 1969 October - 1986 May (Box 1:, Folder 27)
    - Kornblum, Alan and Cinda, ca. 1971 - 1982 November (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - L, 1978 August - 1981 October (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - Laurence Pollinger Limited, 1959 August - 1969 November (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    - M, 1961 August - 1990 February (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - N, 1974 June (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - National Writers Union, 1986 November - 1987 February (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - O, 1978 March (Box 3:, Folder 34)
    - O'Hara, Frank, undated, 1964 April (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - O'Hara, Frank, undated (Box 17:, Folder 629)
    - P, 1969 - 1989 November (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - Pantheon Books, ca. 1964-1965 (Box 2:, Folder 37)
    - Peters, Bob and Meredith, ca. 1960 January (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - R, 1966 January - 1989 June (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - Robert Keeshan Associates, 1964 February (Box 2:, Folder 40)
    - S, 1948 November - 1990 July (Box 2:, Folder 41)
    - Scholastic, 1966 June - 1987 November (Box 2:, Folder 42)
    - Shur, Norman, 1963 November - 1970 March (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - Sendak, Maurice, 1954 December - 1957 July (Box 2:, Folder 44)
    - Shoe String Press, 1989 April - September (Box 2:, Folder 45)
    - Simon and Schuster, 1947 June (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - Something Else Press, 1968 January - February (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - Stagakis, Nina and Stelios, 1982 January - 1983 December (Box 2:, Folder 48)
      [Nina Stagakis is the married name of Nina Wallace, see folder 1:53. Dr. Phil Nel dates some of the undated letters in this folder. See Dr. Nel's notes for more details.]
    - T, 1967 September - 1990 August (Box 2:, Folder 49)
    - Thomas, Bill, 1968 October - 1983 May (Box 2:, Folder 50)
    - United Sisters, undated (Box 2:, Folder 51)
    - V, 1971 February - 1977 August (Box 2:, Folder 52)
    - W [Contains letters from Nina Wallace Stagakis], 1951 March - 1986 August (Box 2:, Folder 53)
    - Western Publishing, 1980 November - 1983 April (Box 2:, Folder 54)
    - Y, 1950 February (Box 2:, Folder 55)
    - Z, 1975 July (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, 1950 July - 1990 June (Box 2:, Folder 57)
      [Dr. Phil Nel's notes identify several of the correspondents here. See Dr. Nel's notes.]
  - Subseries B: Correspondence from Krauss, undated, 1958-1987
    - A - H, 1958 May - 1986 December (Box 2:, Folder 58)
    - Hoffman, Phyllis (Scholastic), 1986 November - 1987 February (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - I - N, 1963 September - 1986 December (Box 2:, Folder 60)
    - O - S, 1962 October - 1986 December (Box 2:, Folder 61)
    - O'Hara, Frank, undated (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - Sendak, Maurice, undated (Box 2:, Folder 63)
    - T - Z, undated (Box 2:, Folder 64)
    - Unidentified Recipients, undated (Box 2:, Folder 65)
- Series II: Children's Literature, undated, 1947-1989
  - [ABC], 1960-1987
    - Preliminary ideas (for workshop), undated (Box 3:, Folder 66)
    - "General Notes", ca. 1967 October [?] (Box 3:, Folder 67)
    - Notes, ca. 1986-1987 [?] (Box 3:, Folder 68)
    - Lists of Possible Titles, undated (Box 3:, Folder 69)
    - "The Nut's ABC," [mss], undated (Box 3:, Folder 70)
    - Early "Happy" versions [mss and tss], undated (Box 3:, Folder 71)
    - "A Father's Alphabet" [tss], undated (Box 3:, Folder 72)
    - Partial drafts, undated, Folder 1 (Box 3:, Folder 73)
    - Partial drafts, undated, Folder 2 (Box 3:, Folder 74)
    - Illustrated partial drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 75)
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 76)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 77)
    - Early manuscript, ca. 1960 (Box 3:, Folder 78)
    - Short versions [tss], ca. 1960 February (Box 3:, Folder 79)
    - Partial typescript, 1960 June 19 (Box 3:, Folder 80)
    - "List of possible... ", ca. 1960 July (Box 3:, Folder 81)
    - List format [tss and copy], 1960 July 4 (Box 3:, Folder 82)
    - "Integration Attempts" [tss], 1960 July 22 - 25 (Box 3:, Folder 83)
    - Early typescript, ca. 1960 July - August (Box 3:, Folder 84)
    - Partial typescript, 1960 August 2 (Box 3:, Folder 85)
    - Partial draft [tss], 1960 August 19 (Box 3:, Folder 86)
    - Partial draft [tss], 1960 August 20 (Box 3:, Folder 87)
    - Partial draft [tss], 1960 August 28 (Box 3:, Folder 88)
    - Partial draft [tss], 1960 August 29 (Box 3:, Folder 89)
    - Partial draft [tss], 1960 August 30 (Box 3:, Folder 90)
    - Partial draft [tss], 1960 September 1 (Box 3:, Folder 91)
    - Partial draft [tss], 1960 September 2 (Box 3:, Folder 92)
    - Partial draft [tss], 1960 September 4 (Box 3:, Folder 93)
    - Typescript and copy, 1960 November 15 (Box 3:, Folder 94)
    - Intermediary typescripts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 95)
    - Typescript, 1968 May 26 (Box 3:, Folder 96)
    - Typescript, ca. 1968 (Box 3:, Folder 97)
    - Typescript, 1970 December (Box 3:, Folder 98)
    - Typescript sent to Nina Stagakis, ca. 1986 December (Box 3:, Folder 99)
    - Annotated typescript and copy, 1987 January (Box 3:, Folder 100)
    - Typescript, ca. 1987 January - February (Box 3:, Folder 101)
    - Typescript and annotated copy, 1987 February 3 (Box 3:, Folder 102)
    - "W Poem" [tss], undated (Box 3:, Folder 103)
    - Illustrations by Krauss, undated (Box 3:, Folder 104)
    - "Do It Yourself ABC" sketches, undated (Box 3:, Folder 105)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 3:, Folder 106)
    - Partial dummies, undated (Box 3:, Folder 107)
    - Complete dumies (2), undated (Box 3:, Folder 108)
    - Typescript dummy, ca. 1987 January - February (Box 3:, Folder 109)
    - Illustrations by Krauss, undated (Box 17:, Folder 632)
    - Illustrations by Nina Stagakis, undated (Box 4:, Folder 110)
    - Illustratoins by Nina Stagakis, undated (Box 18:, Folder 649)
    - Paste-ups and copies, undated (Box 4:, Folder 111)
    - Paste-ups, undated (Box 17:, Folder 630)
  - ABCDEFG
    - Early annotated typescript, undated (Box 4:, Folder 112)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 4:, Folder 113)
    - Sketch dummy, undated (Box 4:, Folder 114)
  - Ah, Ashcan! (unpublished), illustrated mss, undated (Box 4:, Folder 115)
  - The Backward Day [tss and copy], undated (Box 4:, Folder 116)
  - "Barry and the Mashed Potatoes" [tss and copy], undated (Box 4:, Folder 117)
  - Bears
    - Typescript, undated (Box 4:, Folder 118)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1981 November 16 (Box 4:, Folder 119)
  - Benjie and David
    - Notes, undated (Box 4:, Folder 120)
    - Early drafts [tss and mss], undated (Box 4:, Folder 121)
    - Typescript A, undated (Box 4:, Folder 122)
    - Typescript B, "First Draft,", undated (Box 4:, Folder 123)
    - Typescript C, undated (Box 4:, Folder 124)
    - Typescript D, undated (Box 4:, Folder 125)
    - Typescript E, 1957 December 14 (Box 4:, Folder 126)
    - Typescript F, 1958 March 17 (Box 4:, Folder 127)
    - Typescript G, undated (Box 4:, Folder 128)
    - Typescript H [copy], [1958] June 20 (Box 4:, Folder 129)
    - Typescript I, 1958 August (Box 4:, Folder 130)
    - Typescript "Second Draft,", undated (Box 4:, Folder 131)
    - Final typescript, 1958 August 30 (Box 4:, Folder 132)
    - Sketches by Krauss, undated (Box 4:, Folder 133)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 4:, Folder 134)
    - Early dummy, undated (Box 4:, Folder 135)
    - "First dummy for David and Benjie,", undated (Box 4:, Folder 136)
    - Large illustrated dummy, undated (Box 4:, Folder 137)
  - Big and Little
    - Notes, undated (Box 4:, Folder 138)
    - "Need" versions [mss and tss], Folder 1, undated (Box 4:, Folder 139)
    - "Need" versions [mss and tss], Folder 2, undated (Box 4:, Folder 140)
    - "Love" versions [mss and tss], undated (Box 4:, Folder 141)
    - Typescript, [1983?] September 22 (Box 4:, Folder 142)
    - Layout sketch, undated (Box 4:, Folder 143)
    - Rough sketch by Krauss, undated (Box 4:, Folder 144)
    - Drawings by Dick Zimmer [copies], undated (Box 4:, Folder 145)
    - Dummy fragments, undated (Box 4:, Folder 146)
    - Partial dummies (5), undated (Box 5:, Folder 147)
    - Early "Need" dummies (2), undated (Box 5:, Folder 148)
    - Small "Need" dummies (7), undated (Box 5:, Folder 149)
    - Medium "Need" dummies (3), undated (Box 5:, Folder 150)
    - Large "Need" dummy, undated (Box 5:, Folder 151)
    - Small "Love" dummies (6), undated (Box 5:, Folder 152)
    - Large "Love" dummy, undated (Box 5:, Folder 153)
  - "Big and Little Boy" [tss], undated (Box 5:, Folder 154)
  - The Big World and the Little House
    - Typescript, undated (Box 5:, Folder 155)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 5:, Folder 156)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 5:, Folder 157)
  - The Birthday Party
    - Annotated typescript, undated (Box 5:, Folder 158)
    - Uncorrected proofs (2 copies), undated (Box 5:, Folder 159)
  - A Bouquet of Littles
    - "A Ternarie of Littles" by Robert Herrick [copy], 1965 (Box 5:, Folder 160)
    - Preliminary manuscripts, undated (Box 5:, Folder 161)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 5:, Folder 162)
    - Near-final draft [tss copy], undated (Box 5:, Folder 163)
    - "Last" draft and copy, 1962 or 1963 May (Box 5:, Folder 164)
    - Early dummy pages, undated (Box 5:, Folder 165)
    - Font and title sketches, undated (Box 5:, Folder 166)
    - Sketches by Krauss, undated (Box 5:, Folder 167)
    - Partial dummies (6), undated (Box 5:, Folder 168)
    - Undated dummies (Box 5:, Folder 169)
    - Typed dummy, ca. 1962 September 15 (Box 5:, Folder 170)
    - Dummy [original and 2 copies], ca. [1962] November 4 (Box 5:, Folder 171)
    - Dummy, [1962] November 10 - 11 (Box 5:, Folder 172)
    - Dummy, [1962] November 11 - 12 (Box 5:, Folder 173)
    - Dummy, ca. 1962 November 13 (Box 5:, Folder 174)
    - "Record of Last Paste-up" and text, undated (Box 5:, Folder 175)
    - Paste-up dummy and photocopy, undated (Box 5:, Folder 176)
    - Galleys, undated (Box OS:, Folder 657)
    - Contact sheet, undated (Box 5:, Folder 177)
  - ["A Boy and Girl Together"] (unpublished) [tss and copies], 1958 April (Box 5:, Folder 178)
  - ["The Boy and the Lion"] [tss], undated (Box 6:, Folder 179)
  - The Bundle Book, proofs [copy], undated (Box 6:, Folder 180)
  - The Carrot Seed
    - Teaching guide, 1989 (Box 6:, Folder 181)
    - Proposal for film, 1987 September 19 (Box 6:, Folder 182)
  - Catalogs, multiple children's works by Krauss[Includes interview, "Ruth Krauss: Let Me Tell You a Story" and article, "Children's Books" by Irma Simonton Black], 1953-1982 (Box 6:, Folder 183)
  - Charlotte and the White Horse
    - Partial typescript, undated (Box 6:, Folder 184)
    - Charlotte the Only Child and Buttermilk [tss], no date (Box 6:, Folder 185)
    - Early typescript, undated (Box 6:, Folder 186)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 6:, Folder 187)
    - Partial Dummy, undated (Box 6:, Folder 188)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 6:, Folder 189)
    - Rough uncorrected proofs, 1976 (Box 6:, Folder 190)
  - ["Chicken Story"] Dummy, undated (Box 6:, Folder 191)
  - Child's Eye View of the World, sketches, undated (Box 6:, Folder 192)
  - Child's Eye Visual, layout sketches, no date (Box 6:, Folder 193)
  - The Cinderella Tree
    - Early typescript, undated (Box 6:, Folder 194)
    - Typescript and copies, ca. 1966 (Box 6:, Folder 195)
    - Submission typescript, 1966 June (Box 6:, Folder 197)
    - Partial dummy, undated (Box 6:, Folder 198)
  - Everychild [tss, mss, layouts], undated (Box 6:, Folder 198a)
  - Everything Under a Mushroom
    - Early typescripts and manuscripts, undated (Box 6:, Folder 200)
    - Later typescripts and manuscripts, undated (Box 6:, Folder 201)
    - Probable final draft with notes, undated (Box 6:, Folder 202)
    - "Additionals" [mss], undated (Box 6:, Folder 203)
    - Typescript sent to publisher, undated (Box 6:, Folder 204)
    - Sketches by unidentified artist, undated (Box 6:, Folder 205)
    - Sketches by Krauss, undated (Box 6:, Folder 206)
    - Color sketch by Krauss, undated (Box 6:, Folder 207)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 6:, Folder 208)
    - Artwork by Margot Tomes and copies, undated (Box 6:, Folder 209)
    - Margot Tomes's illustrations and text [copies], undated (Box 17:, Folder 631)
    - Krauss's comments on Tomes's illustrations, undated (Box 6:, Folder 210)
    - Small dummies, undated (Box 6:, Folder 211)
    - Medium illustrated dummies, undated (Box 6:, Folder 212)
    - Large illustrated dummies and copies, undated (Box 6:, Folder 213)
    - Large illustrated dummy, "Last One,", undated (Box 6:, Folder 214)
    - Corrected copy, 1973 (Box 6:, Folder 215)
    - Catalogs, undated (Box 6:, Folder 216)
  - Eyes Nose Fingers Toes
    - Undated typescripts and manuscripts (Box 7:, Folder 217)
    - Typescript, 1958 February 12 (Box 7:, Folder 218)
    - Typescript, manuscript, and notes, 1958 March (Box 7:, Folder 219)
    - Manuscript and notes, 1959 April 19 (Box 7:, Folder 220)
    - Typescript, 1963 June 1 (Box 7:, Folder 221)
    - Final typescript and copy, annotated, undated (Box 7:, Folder 222)
    - Contract notes, 1962 July (Box 7:, Folder 223)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 7:, Folder 224)
    - Layout sketches and notes on layout, 1959 February (Box 7:, Folder 225)
    - Two-part illustration, undated (Box 7:, Folder 226)
    - Illustrated dummies, ca. 1964 January (Box 7:, Folder 227)
    - Paste-up dummies and copy, 1964 April (Box 7:, Folder 228)
    - Uncorrected galleys, ca. 1964 (Box 17:, Folder 663)
    - Proofs, 1964 July (Box 7:, Folder 229)
  - "Families," illustrated manuscript fragments, undated (Box 7:, Folder 230)
  - First Book of Monsters
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 7:, Folder 231)
    - Typescripts, 1984 July - November (Box 7:, Folder 232)
    - Dummies (2) and copies, undated (Box 7:, Folder 233)
  - [Flood Picture Book] (unpublished)
    - Partial typescript and copy, undated (Box 7:, Folder 233a)
    - Pasted typescript A and copy, undated (Box 7:, Folder 233b)
    - Pasted typescript B and copy, undated (Box 7:, Folder 233c)
    - Final typescript, undated (Box 7:, Folder 233d)
    - Dummies, undated (Box 7:, Folder 233e)
    - Large color dummy, undated (Box 7:, Folder 233f)
    - Tracings by Crockett Johnson, undated (Box 18:, Folder 656)
  - A Good Man and His Good Wife
    - Typescript for printer, undated (Box 7:, Folder 234)
    - "The Live-Togethers" (gender revised version) [tss], undated (Box 7:, Folder 236)
    - Artwork by Marc Simont, undated (Box 7:, Folder 237)
    - Rough paste-up dummy and copy, undated (Box 7:, Folder 238)
    - Illustrated dummy, undated (Box 7:, Folder 239)
    - Mechanical page, undated (Box 7:, Folder 240)
  - Good Things to Know and Interesting Things to Think About [tss], undated (Box 7:, Folder 241)
  - The Great Duffy
    - "The Writing of the Great Duffy,", undated (Box 7:, Folder 242)
    - Movie treatment [tss], undated (Box 7:, Folder 242a)
  - The Growing Story
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 7:, Folder 243)
    - Pasted typescript and copy, undated (Box 7:, Folder 244)
    - Photocopy of book, undated (Box 7:, Folder 245)
  - The Happy Day
    - Typescripts and manuscripts, undated (Box 7:, Folder 246)
    - Illustrations by Krauss, undated (Box 7:, Folder 247)
    - Catalog, 1983 (Box 7:, Folder 248)
  - The Happy Egg
    - Notes, undated (Box 7:, Folder 249)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 7:, Folder 250)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 7:, Folder 251)
    - Printing of text, undated (Box 7:, Folder 252)
    - Sketches by Crockett Johnson, undated (Box 8:, Folder 253)
    - Title sketches, undated (Box 8:, Folder 254)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 8:, Folder 255)
    - Partial dummy (annotated by Ann McGovern?), 1966 June 1 (Box 8:, Folder 256)
    - Small dummies (3), undated (Box 8:, Folder 257)
    - Paste-up dummy, undated (Box 8:, Folder 258)
    - Copies of paste-up dummy, annotated, undated (Box 8:, Folder 259)
    - Mechanicals, ca. 1967 (Box 17:, Folder 634)
    - Photocopy of first edition (incomplete), undated (Box 8:, Folder 260)
  - A Hole Is to Dig
    - Correspondence [Dr. Phil Nel's notes identify some of the correspondents here. See Dr. Nel's notes.], ca. 1952 (Box 8:, Folder 260a)
    - Teacher's notes, 1951 January 11 - 12 (Box 8:, Folder 261)
    - Krauss's notes, undated (Box 8:, Folder 262)
    - Manuscripts [Includes some sketches by Maurice Sendak.], undated (Box 8:, Folder 263)
    - "List of Definitions" [tss and copies], ca. 1952 February 26 (Box 8:, Folder 264)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 8:, Folder 265)
    - Text of first dummy [tss and copy], undated (Box 8:, Folder 266)
    - Late typescript, undated (Box 8:, Folder 267)
    - Final typescript, annotated, undated (Box 8:, Folder 268)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 8:, Folder 269)
    - Layout sketches by Maurice Sendak, undated (Box 8:, Folder 270)
    - Layout sketch, oversize, undated (Box 17:, Folder 635)